The Targeted Sharingan
（ダンゾウ）写輪眼というものは
そもそも　使い捨ての力だ。
The Sharingan is a disposable power.
（ダンゾウ）写輪眼を持つ
うちは一族の者たちですら→
Even the Uchiha Clan
who possess the Sharingan…
力を使えば使うほど
その瞳力を失い→
The more they use that power,
the greater the loss of their eyesight…
やがて　光すら失うという。
until they finally go blind.
ましてや　写輪眼そのものを
失うことによって発動する→
Furthermore, there is even
a Forbidden Jutsu
that is invoked at the cost
of losing the Sharingan.
禁術まであるのだからな。
わしの　この眼の代わりを
手に入れてこい。
Get me a replacement for
this right eye of mine.
うちはの者を襲うのであれば
周到な準備が必要かと。
If we are to attack
a member of the Uchiha,
careful preparation is necessary.
うちはの者にあらず　親も師もなく
友を殺した者が→
There is one
who is not an Uchiha…
who has neither parents nor teachers,
who has killed his own comrade…
写輪眼を一つ持っている。
（甲）はたけカカシ。
Kakashi…Hatake.
後腐れはない。
Then we won't need to worry
about any future trouble.
RIN NOHARA
誰の墓？
Whose grave is it?
The friend he killed.
アイツが殺した自分の仲間だ。
（夕顔）カカシ先輩。
Kakashi Senpai…
（夕顔）火影様がお呼びです。
Lord Hokage is calling.
（カカシ）わかった。
All right.
いい加減　先輩はよせ
アカデミーじゃないんだぞ。
Stop calling me "Senpai."
This isn't the academy.
暗部でも先輩じゃありませんか。
You're still my senior in the ANBU.
私　先輩をお手本にしています。
Besides, you're my role model.
もっとマシなヤツを手本にしろ。
Find someone more suitable.
おい。
Hey…
のはらリン。
RIN NOHARA
Rin Nohara…
大蛇丸が　国のあちこちに
秘密の研究施設を→
You are aware that Orochimaru
has secret research facilities
scattered throughout the country,
aren't you?
持っていたことは知っておるな。
はい。
Yes.
里抜けの際　大蛇丸は
そのいくつかを破壊し→
After he deserted the village,
he destroyed some and
kept some intact.
いくつかを
そのままに残していきおった。
わしらの知らぬものも含めてな。
Including ones that
we have no knowledge of.
そのようですね。
It seems that way.
任務中の小隊が　偶然に
正体不明の施設を発見した。
A small battalion on a mission came
upon such a facility by accident.
帰還した小隊の報告によれば→
According to their report
upon their return,
どうやら　大蛇丸が遺棄していった
研究施設の一つらしい。
it seems to be a research facility
that was abandoned by Orochimaru.
小隊は　中を調べたのですか？
Did they go inside and investigate?
幸いにして　まだじゃ。
Fortunately, not yet.
何があるか　わかりませんからね。
Right, since we don't know
what's inside.
わしは　あやつの
おぞましき研究の中身を→
I do not want members
of our village
to learn about his repulsive
research activities…
里の者に知られたくないのじゃ。
行方不明になった肉親や仲間が
どうなったのかをな。
of what happened to
their missing kin and friends.
However, an investigation is necessary.
だが　調査の必要はある。
そこで　俺にというわけですね。
So, you want me to go?
It's been three years since
Orochimaru left the village.
大蛇丸が里抜けしてから
３年も経つが→
いまだに　あやつの負の遺産に
悩まされる。
But he still remains
a thorn in our side.
すまぬが頼むぞ。
はっ。
I hate to ask you,
but please take care of this.
Yes, sir.
大蛇丸のアジトを見つけたそうだな。
I understand Orochimaru's hideout
was found.
あやつの残した研究施設だ
すでに調査要員を派遣した。
It's one of his research facilities.
I've dispatched someone
to investigate.
そうか。
何か気がかりでも？
I see…
Is something troubling you?
捨ておかれた研究施設とはいえ
ヤツはトラップを残したかもしれん。
He could have set some kind
of trap before abandoning it.
その調査役は　大丈夫かとな。
Are you sure it's safe
to investigate?
I sent an experienced and
qualified ANBU agent.
暗部の手だれを派遣した。
何事もなければよいな。
I hope nothing goes amiss.
SEAL
うっ！
お前…　甲か。
Is that you, Kinoe?!
お久しぶりですね　カカシさん。
It's been awhile, Kakashi.
どうして　ここに？
任務ですから。
What are you doing here?
I'm on a mission.
俺のバックアップに？
As my back-up?
いや　違うな。
No, that isn't it.
ダンゾウ様か。
Did Lord Danzo dispatch
a Foundation shinobi,
大蛇丸の研究施設を
自分たちでも調べようと→
because he's interested in
Orochimaru's research facility?
根を派遣した？
根の者は任務を
何もしゃべらないか。
Foundation shinobi never discuss
their mission… Is that it?
だが　何にせよ助かった。
No matter.
You did help me out there.
カカシさんが燃えてしまっては
僕も困ります。
We can't have you burned
to a crisp.
一緒に中を調査するか？
Do you want to investigate
what's inside together?
お互い何か発見したら
情報は伝え合うということで。
Whatever we find,
we'll share the intel with each other.
どうした？
What's wrong?
部署は違っても同じ木ノ葉の忍だ。
We may work in different divisions,
but we're Leaf shinobi.
協力しても　いいんじゃないか？
Let's cooperate.
そうですね。
Yes…
Who knows if a demon or
a snake will appear?
鬼が出るか蛇が出るか
わかりません。
一緒に行きましょうか。
よし。
Let's go together.
Right.
トラップは入り口のあれ
１つのようだな。
The only trap seems to have been
that one by the entrance.
大蛇丸も逃げるにあたって
時間はなかったはずだ。
Orochimaru was pressed
for time in his rush to escape.
そうですね。　でも用心は必要です。
You're right.
Still, we must be careful.
あぁ。
Yeah…
行くぞ。
はい。
Let's go.
Right.
何もありませんね。
There's nothing in here.
大蛇丸は　ここで
何の実験をしていたんだ？
What was Orochimaru
experimenting on in here?
お得意の人体実験の
たぐいだろうが…。
Probably doing what
he does best.
Experimenting on
human test subjects...
人体実験…。
Human test subjects…
((大蛇丸：これもダメ。
This one's no good.
あれも　それも。
This one as well.
That one too…
どれもダメ。
They're all no good…
この人体実験は失敗ね。
This human experiment is a failure.
成長期の子供のほうが→
I thought that an adolescent
would adjust far better
柱間細胞の増殖に
適応するかと思ったけど。
in propagating Hashirama's cells, but…
逆にダメね。
But it's just the opposite.
子供じゃ体力もなく
耐えきれないわ。
A child doesn't have the strength
or stamina to endure it.
ここは　もう
閉鎖するしかないわね。
I guess I'll have to
shut this place down.
《待って》
Wait!
But not to worry.
（大蛇丸）心配しなくていいわよ。
細胞の移植には
他の方法も　いろいろあるわ。
There are many more ways
of cell implantation.
(すぐに次の実験を始めるから))
I'll start the next test right away.
《待って　待って　待って！》
Wait, wait…
Wait!
甲…。
Ki…noe.
おい　甲　行くぞ！
Hey, Kinoe.
Let's go.
はい。
Right.
ここは鍵が　かかっている。
This one's locked.
Leave it to me.
任せてください。
開きましたよ。
It's open.
木ノ葉の里からたえて久しい
その術→
That jutsu went extinct in
the Hidden Leaf Village ages ago.
So how did you learn it?
お前　どうやって覚えたんだ？
It's a secret.
秘密です。
木遁術は木ノ葉にとって
重要な意味を持つ。
Are you aware that
the Wood Style jutsu
is extremely important to
the Hidden Leaf?
それを知っているか？
さぁ。
I didn't know that.
木ノ葉には九尾の人柱力がいる。
The Jinchuriki of the Nine Tails
belongs to the Hidden Leaf.
木遁術は九尾をコントロールできる
力のひとつだ。
The Wood Style Jutsu is
one of the powers
that can control the Nine Tails.
もうひとつが
写輪眼だということは→
I know that the Sharingan
is the other power.
知っています。
お前の木遁術は根だけでなく→
Your Wood Style Jutsu isn't just
for the Foundation…
It is a power meant to serve
all of Hidden Leaf Village.
もっと広く木ノ葉の里
全体のためになる力だ。
ダンゾウ様は　お前を手もとに
置いておきたいのだろうが→
Lord Danzo wants to
keep you at his side.
But you are more suited
to working directly under the Hokage.
本来なら火影直轄のほうが
ふさわしいはずだ。
お前も根ではなく→
Don't you want to leave
the Foundation
and come out of the shadows?
もっと日の当たる場所に
出たくないか？
No…no… I'm still alive!
《イヤだ　イヤだ。
まだ僕は生きてる！》
《イヤだ…》
N-No…
((ダンゾウ：生き残りか))
There's a survivor?!
何だ　これは？
What is this?
中に何かあるぞ。
There's something's inside.
何の真似だ　甲！？
What's going on, Kinoe?!
甲！
Kinoe!
お前　本気か！？
Are you serious?!
はい　本気です！
Yes, I'm serious!
《先手はとった　あとは…》
I have the advantage.
All that's left is…
《アイツ　写輪眼との
戦い方を知っている。
He knows how to fight
against my Sharingan.
最初から　やる気で…》
This was his intent
from the very beginning…
甲！　お前が本気で
俺を殺そうというのなら→
Kinoe!
If you're serious about killing me,
then I won't hold back!
俺も本気だ！
仲間同士で殺し合いだぞ！
It will be a death match,
friend against friend!
本気です。
I'm serious.
本気で来たんです！
I'm dead serious!
ううっ！
なぜ俺の命を狙う！？
Why do you want to kill me?
任務ですから。
It's my mission.
仲間の命を狙う任務などあるか！？
What kind of mission sends
a friend after a friend?!
変なこと言いますね。
You're one to talk.
仲間殺しの
カカシさんともあろう人が。
You're the one who killed a friend.
分身！？
A substitute?!
木遁分身…
あの頃より腕を上げたな。
Wood Style Substitute…
You've gotten better
since the last time…
ええ　だから
カカシさんも本気でどうぞ。
Yes. So don't hold back, Kakashi.
俺は仲間を殺さない！
I won't kill a friend!
遠慮ならいりません。
No need to hold back!
やめろ　甲！
この任務は放棄しろ！
Stop, Kinoe! Abandon this mission!
忍にとって任務は絶対です！
A shinobi's mission is absolute!
甲！
Kinoe!
任務は絶対じゃない！
A mission is not absolute!
仲間を殺せというのが任務ならば
その任務は間違いだ。
If your orders are to kill a friend…
that order is wrong!
お前に　そう命じたヤツが
間違っている！
The one who gave you
such an order is wrong.
《ダンゾウ様が間違っている？》
Is Lord Danzo wrong?
((歩けるか？
Can you walk?
どうした？　己が誰かを
忘れているようだが→
What's the matter?
You don't seem to remember
who you are…
言葉まで忘れたか？
but have you forgotten
how to talk as well?
あ…　いえ。
Uh, no…
ついてこい。
Follow me.
大蛇丸は欲張りすぎだ。
Orochimaru is greedy.
次々と新しいことを
試すのはよいが→
It's good to have the desire
to test out new things,
見切りも早すぎる。
but he gives up too quickly.
だが　お前は見切りを
つけられて幸いであったな。
However, you're lucky
he gave up on you.
大蛇丸のもとにおれば→
If you had stayed
with Orochimaru,
更なる実験の材料に
されていたであろう。
you would have ended up
another test subject.
わしの組織は
行き場をなくした忍たちを→
My organization takes in shinobi
who have nowhere to go.
引き取っている。
お前も　これより→
From now on, you will be
a shinobi of the Foundation.
根の忍となるがいい。
根？
The Foundation?
そうだ　わしらは
この木ノ葉の里という→
Yes. We are the tenacious Foundation.
We support the great tree known
as the Village Hidden in the Leaves.
大木を支える頑強な根だ。
根が十分に張らなければ
巨木は育たぬ。
Without strong roots,
a large tree cannot grow.
だから　根…。
That's why the Foundation…
お前は甲と名乗るがよい。
You will be called Kinoe.
お前も　これから
わしらの仲間だ。
Henceforth, you are one of us.
６０分の１だ。
え？
You were one of 60.
Huh?
木遁使いを生み出すために
他の５９人の子供が失われたのだ。
In order to produce a Wood Style user,
59 other children have been lost…
甲よ　その命　大事にしろよ。
Kinoe, cherish your life.
はい。
Yes.
行ってくるよ。　僕は
木ノ葉の根っこになるんだって。
I'm leaving.
He said I'm going to be one of
the Foundation of the Hidden Leaf.
水遁！
Water Style!
チャクラをだいぶ
練られるようになったな。
You're able to infuse chakra
quite nicely now.
Yes!
はい！
All right. I shall train you myself.
ようし！
そろそろ　わしが鍛えてやろう。
ダンゾウ様が！？
自ら！？
Lord Danzo is? Directly?
直接？
Personally?
わしはかつて
初代火影様の戦いを見た。
I once saw the First Hokage
in battle.
樹界降誕　花樹海降臨。
Deep Forest Emergence...
Deep Forest Bloom…
いずれも強力な木遁忍術であった。
Such formidable
Wood Style Ninjutsu.
その細胞を受けついだ
お前ならと思っている。
If you have inherited his cells,
I put all my hopes in you…
Manipulate the Earth Style
and Water Style
土遁　水遁の性質変化を
同時に扱うのだ。
Change in Chakra Nature
simultaneously!
まだ無理か。
すみません。
Not quite yet.
I'm sorry.
しかたあるまい。
It can't be helped.
You are not an exact copy
of the First Hokage.
お前は　初代様の完全なコピーでは
ないのだからなぁ。
これは　初代様が残した
木遁の忍術書だ。
Here is the Ninjutsu Scroll left
by the First Hokage.
わしには使えぬ術ばかりだが→
It's full of jutsu that I can't use,
but you should be able
to learn them.
お前ならば　習得できるであろう。
ダンゾウ様にできない術を僕が？
Me? Learn jutsu that you cannot,
Lord Danzo?
忍の世界には
いくつもの力がひしめいている。
The world of the shinobi is filled
with a myriad of jutsu.
ゆえに一つの力では対抗できぬ。
You cannot compete
with just one power.
複数の力を融合し→
We must master various jutsu
and use those powers
to unite the shinobi world.
その力をもって
忍世界の統一をはからねばならぬ。
(お前の木遁忍術に
期待しているぞ))
I have high hopes
for your Wood Style Jutsu.
ダンゾウ様は間違っていない！
Lord Danzo is not wrong!
任務を遂行する！
I will fulfill my mission!
この！
あっ！
何が任務だ！
もう一度　言う！
仲間を殺す任務なんてない！
だったら
あなたは　なんで殺した？
なに！？
のはらリンを　なんで殺した！
なんで殺した？
任務だから殺したんだろう！
勝手に　リンの名を口にするな！
俺は暗部の任務で
木ノ葉の抜け忍や→
裏切り者を処分してきた。
仲間殺しのカカシ。
そう呼ばれて当然だ。
だがな！
俺は　リンを…。
このっ！
殺したくなんかなかった！
俺は仲間を守れなかった。
だから　リンは死んだ。
この千鳥で！
守れなかった？
守れなかった…。
僕を　殺しますか？
お前は　木ノ葉の仲間か？
それとも裏切り者か？
裏切り者ではありません。
では　なんだ？
僕は　根の甲。
なら甲　根の任務を放棄しろ。
できません。
では　お前を拘束し
火影様に引き渡す。
好きに…　してください。
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では　最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！にっぽんの歌』。
（松丸）今回は　ご覧の
豪華な歌手の皆さんによる→
華麗なステージをお届けいたします。
皆さん　どうぞ
よろしくお願いいたします。